Guide to the Fredericka Martin Photograph Collection ALBA.PHOTO.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Fredericka Martin Photographs
circa 1936-1975
bulk
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Martin, Fredericka I.
Briggs, Judson Reynolds, 1906-
ALBA.PHOTO.001
4.25 Linear Feet in 11 boxes
Fredericka (Freddie) Imogene Martin (1905-1992) was chief nurse and administrator of the American medical volunteers who served during the Spanish Civil War. Following the war, Martin worked on the Pribilof Islands in the Bering Sea, becoming spokesperson and advocate for the indigenous Aleut sealing community. Most of the images in this collection were accrued by Martin in the course of her work as a nurse in Spain. The collection includes portraits and images of many American medical volunteers including: Edward Barsky, Ave Bruzzichesi, Irving Busch, Ruth Davidow, Joseph Dhago (Jose Dhaga), May Edythe Dyer, Leo Eloesser, A.I. Friedman, Lini M.De Vries (a.k.a. Leni Fuhr), Philip Pakier Goland, Rose Sara Goldblatt, Fanny Golub, Ray Harris, Rose Margaret Harvan, Toby Jensky, Salaria Kea, Rebecca Schulman, Anne Shuldiner, Anne Taft, Lenora Temple, Sidney Vogel and Oscar Israel Weissman. The collection also contains images of the mobile hospital/autochir, injured/recovering soldiers and surgeries.
Approximately 4,000 black and white photographs sized from 1 ½ x 1 ½ to 10 x 13 ½ inches; approximately 240 black and white negatives sized from 1 ½ x 1 to 2 ½ x 4 ¼ inches; one 35mm color slide
Provenance
The Fredericka Martin Collection was donated to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives by Martin's daughter Tobyanne Berenberg in 1991. This collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University. The images in the Martin Photograph Collection were separated from the Martin manuscript collection at the time of processing.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Historical/Biographical Note
Fredericka (Freddie) Imogene Martin (1905-1992) was chief nurse and administrator of the American medical volunteers who served during the Spanish Civil War. Under the leadership of surgeon Dr. Edward Barsky, Martin served as chief nurse and administrator of the American Hospital division. The first unit traveled with four ambulances, 12 tons of medical supplies and all the necessary equipment to outfit a 50-bed hospital. During her period of service, Martin supervised the work of fifty-four nurses, aided in the organization of six American hospitals on four fronts, and helped set up a mobile operating unit. For further biographical information on Martin, and to review the scope and contents of his manuscript collection see, Guide to the Fredericka Martin Papers, ALBA 1
Scope and Content Note
Series I: Photographs. The collection contains approximately 4,000 images emphasizing the role of the Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy in the Spanish Civil War, including images of the mobile hospital/autochir, injured/recovering soldiers and surgeries. The collection includes portraits and images of many American medical volunteers including: Edward Barsky, Ave Bruzzichesi, Irving Busch, Ruth Davidow, Joseph Dhago (Jose Dhaga), May Edythe Dyer, Leo Eloesser, A.I. Friedman, Lini M.De Vries (a.k.a. Leni Fuhr), Philip Pakier Goland, Rose Sara Goldblatt, Fanny Golub, Ray Harris, Rose Margaret Harvan, Toby Jensky, Salaria Kee (a.k.a. Salaria Kea), Rebecca Schulman, Anne Shuldiner, Anne Taft, Lenora Temple, Sidney Vogel and Oscar Israel Weissman. The collection contains images of 20 hospitals, with most representing the hospital at Villa Paz. The collection also includes non-combat photographs of American and other volunteers relaxing and engaging in day-to-day activities.
Series II: Negatives and Slide. The collection contains approximately 240 negatives and one 35mm slide. The negatives and slides are stored separately from the photographs. Thirteen negatives match prints in the collection. The negative sleeve will indicate if a negative matches a print. The matching print will bear the notation "have neg." The negatives emphasize the role of the Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy in the Spanish Civil War including images of ambulances and soldiers engaging in day-to-day activities. The collection includes portraits and images of many American medical volunteers including: Edward Barsky, Joseph Dhago (José Dhaga), May Edythe Dyer, Leo Eloesser, Lini M.De Vries (a.k.a. Leni Fuhr), Philip Pakier Goland, Evelyn Hutchins, Salaria Kee (a.k.a. Salaria Kea) and Karl Rahman. The negative series also contains images of bombed/shelled buildings, injured/recovering patients and Alcoy Hospital, Benicasim Hospital, and El Escorial Hospital.
Series III: Photo Albums. There is one 8 ¾ x 6 ½ red photo album and one 13 ½ x 9 ¼ green photo album. The red album contains roughly 25 images of AMB and International Medical personnel relaxing and engaging in day-to-day activities; included are ambulances, Martin, Ernesto Amann, Otto Schilling, and Oscar Weissman. The album also contains images of Albert Maltz and Martin's family in the United States The green album contains approximately 50 images of AMB and International Medical personnel conducting a surgery, relaxing and engaging in day-to-day activities, non-combat activities at the Ebro Front, ambulances and other medical vehicles, the interior of the mobile hospital/autochir, one image of a downed airplane and Spanish panoramas. Most of the individuals in the prints are identified, including, Max William Binn, Andy Borysko, Roy Braden, Jack Carpenter, George Chilingarian, Percy Cohen, Dancho Draganoff, Harry Evans, Ted Gibbs, Council Gibson, Fanny Golub, Ken Graeber, Nan Green, Almon Gregovic, Fritz Grell, Captain Grossfelt, Dr. Hine, Mac Kraus, Ed Lending, Joe Maier, William Howard Mason, Helge Meyer, James Neugass, Frank Pasker, Jack Penrod, William Winston Pike, Mildred Rackley, Carl Rahman, Norman C. Rintz, R. Schechter [?], Max Silverman, Harold Smith, Randall B. "Pete" Smith, Len Spencer (Joe Baron), ? Van Born, George Watt, and J. Leigh White. There is also one image taken outside of Spain of an ambulance donated to the American Medical Bureau by a group of individuals in the movie industry. The following individuals are identified in the print: Conrad Bercovici, J. Edward Bromberg, Nancy Carrol, director and Mrs. Frank Tuttle, nurse Rier, Gale Sondergaard, director Herbert Biberman
Arrangement
Folders arranged alphabetically by topic in series I and II.
The files are grouped into three series:
Missing Title
I, Photographs
II, Negatives and Slide
III, Photo Albums
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Fredericka Martin Papers, ALBA 1
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Hospitals.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Medical care.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Women.; Negatives (photographic); Political prisoners |z Spain.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x African Americans.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Children.; Barcelona (Spain); Black-and-white photographs.; Cuernavaca (Mexico); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Schulman, Rebecca (Durem); North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy.; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln Battalion.; Shuldiner, Anne.; Taft, Anne, 1912-1990; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Brigada Internacional, XV.; Vanzant, Frances; Temple, Lenora; Jensky, Toby, 1911-1995; Harvan, Rose Margaret.; Maas, Johana; Kea, Salaria (O'Reilly); Martin, Fredericka I.; Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy.; Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy.; Dhago, Joseph; Dyer, May Edythe; Eloesser, Leo; Friedman, A. I.; Goland, Philip Pakier; Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives; Goldblatt, Rose Sara.; Golub, Fanny; Harris, Ray.; Vogel, Sidney; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.; Amann, Ernesto; Weissman, Oscar Israel; Barsky, Edward K., 1895-1975; Bruzzichesi, Ave; Busch, Irving; De Vries, Lini M.
- Series I: Photographs, circa 1937-1938
  - ?, Abie: Albanian Volunteer, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alcoy Hospital: Buildings, May 26, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alhambra Hospital: Buildings, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alicante Hospital: Operating Room, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Amann, Ernesto: Examination Room with Ursula Mayer Amann and Unidentified Doctor, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Amann, Ernesto: Portrait, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amann, Ernesto: With Unidentified Child, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Friends of Spanish Democracy: Medical Unit, Ambulance, Nov 30, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Friends of Spanish Democracy: Warehouse in New York, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Medical Bureau (AMB): ?, Oscar Weissman, Otto Schilling, Rose Waxman, [Dr. Ettleson?], Cerbere (France), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - AMB: Ambulances/Mobile Hospital, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - AMB: Anne Taft, [Phil Solar?], ?, ?, [Seguro de los Banos?], circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - AMB: Anne Taft, Sally Kahn, Harry Wilkes, Odio Perez, Philip Pakier Goland, Lini M.De Vries (a.k.a. Leni Fuhr), Barcelona, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - AMB: Autochir/Mobile Hospital, Edna Sanford, Jacque ?, Charlie ?, Prior to Crossing Ebro, Jul 1, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - AMB: Autochir/Mobile Hospital, Irving Busch, Congressman Bernard with Five Others, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - AMB: Ave Bruzzichesi and Alice Wagnon, Benicasim, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - AMB: Ave Bruzzichesi, Edward Barsky, Katherine Purviance, Leo Eloesser, James Neugass, Edwin S. Weisfield, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - AMB: California Doctors, Edward Barsky (second from left) and Three Unidentified Doctors, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - AMB: Clara Leight, Toby Jensky, Anne Shuldiner, Hannah Herskowitz, Rose Wachsman with Two Others, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - AMB: Edward Barsky, A. I. Friedman, Oscar Israel Weissman, ?, Albert Byrne, Irving Busch, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - AMB: Edwin Wiesfield, Frances Vanzant, Leonard H. Larsen, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - AMB: En Route to Spain, Dorothy Fontaine, [Claire Leight?], Hanna Herskowitz, Anne Shuldiner, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - AMB: En Route to Spain, S.S. Aquitania with Spanish Medical Personnel, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - AMB: En Route to Spain, S.S. Normandie with Florence Pike (a.k.a. Florence Mildred Tew), Dorothy Fontaine, Abraham Ettleson, Leigh White, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - AMB: En Route to Spain, S.S. Normandie with Hilda Bell, A.N. Townsen, Richard Chodoff, Rose Harvan, Albacete, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - AMB: En Route to Spain, S.S. Normandie with Hilda Bell, Dr. Stadt, Sebastian Gomez, ? Prieto, ? Balans, May 1, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - AMB: En Route to Spain, S.S. Normandie with Rose Waxman, Helene Weissman, Toby Jensky, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - AMB: En Route to Spain, S.S. Normandie with Unidentified Medical Personnel, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - AMB: En Route to Spain, Group, Unidentified, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - AMB: Fanny Golub, Lenora Temple, Cleo Cannon Duncan, Anne Taft, Mary Rader, Edyth May Dyer, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - AMB: Fredericka Martin, Eduardo Odio Perez, Alan Sarrelll, Edward Barsky, Mildred Rackley, Anne Taft, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - AMB: Fredericka Martin, Martin Hourihan, "Marty" Chauffeur of the Autochir, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - AMB: Group, Four Unidentified Women, Lewis I. Cohen, ?, ?, Jack Goldstein, Leo Eloesser, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - AMB: Group, Grace Berkowitz and Three Unidentified Nurses, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - AMB: Group, Lenora Temple, Irving Busch with Five Others, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - AMB: "Group Ten", circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - AMB: Groups, Unidentified, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - AMB: Headquarters, Far Rockaway, NY, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - AMB: Helen Freeman and Toby Jensky, Relaxing, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - AMB: Irving Busch, Oscar Israel Weissman, Albert Byrne, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - AMB: Lini M.De Vries (a.k.a. Leni Fuhr), ?, Barcelona, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - AMB: Personnel in the U.S., circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - AMB: Ray Harris, Lini M.De Vries (a.k.a. Leni Fuhr), Edward Barsky, Rose F., Helen Freeman, Harry Wilkes, Philip Pakier Goland, Barcelona, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - AMB: Rose Sara Goldblatt, Nora Temple, Evelyn Hutchins, Fanny Golub, Bertha F. Kipness, ?, Salaria Kee (a.k.a. Salaria Kea, later O'Reilly), Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - AMB: (First Row) Rose Sara Goldblatt, Rose Waxman, Evelyn Hutchins, Nora Temple, Fannie Golub; (Second Row) Grace Berkowitz, Salaria Kee (a.k.a. Salaria Kea), Sonia Merino; (Third Row) Donald Pitts, ?, ?, Morris Kornblum, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - AMB: Ruth Davidow and Leonard H. Larsen, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - AMB: Shipboard, Return from Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - AMB: Speaking Tour, Harry Robinson with Five Others, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - AMB: "Third Group", circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Animals: Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - At the Front, Combat: Artillery/Mortar Crew, Alicante, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Andy Barysko, Stanley Matajunas, and ?, Jun 1937-Jul 1937 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Australian Volunteers, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Bob Nagel and Mac Kraus Digging a Trench, Ebro, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Digging Trench, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Dor Weissman, Louis Bernstein, Mike Hill, Joe Hecht, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Group, Ebro Offensive, Apr 21, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Engineer/Surveyor, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Group, ? Friedman and ?, Marca, Jun 1937-Jul 1937 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Group, Benicasim, Apr 20, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Jean Percone, Salvador Guardiola, Jose Vinceza, Antonio Martin, John Kizely, Mois?É¬©s Vall?É¬©s Broggi, Dr. Boulkan, Alfonso Denia, Fausto Gonzalez, Jose Jordana, Felipe Weiss, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Kitchen, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Lecture at Southern Front, Cordoba, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: M. Zacahary Stadt, Major Johnson, Helene Weisman, Dr. Posner, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Timoteo Moreno, Amadeo ?, Marcelina Gonzalez, Esther Goldstein, Mois?É¬©s Vall?É¬©s Broggi, Dorothy Rutter, Irene Silverstein, Vicente ?, Lolita ?, Michael Tabaka, Jose Jordana, Salvador Guardiola, ?, Gra?É¬±en, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - At the Front, Non-Combat: Ted Veldfort and Elliot Loomis Digging Trench, Ebro, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Audell, Evelyn: With Nurses, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Ayers, Frank: Seated with ?, ?. Not in Spain, undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Aza?É¬±a, Manuel: Portrait (Dedication to Joseph Dhago), circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Barsky, Edward: Anne Taft, Cuevas Labradas, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Barsky, Edward: Groups, Not in Spain, undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Barsky, Edward: Group, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Barsky, Edward: Operating on a Patient, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Barsky, Edward: Portrait, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Barsky, Edward: Portrait with Rudolfo ?, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Barsky, Edward: Standing next to Car, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Barsky, Edward: Surgery, Anne Taft, Albert Byrne, Ray Harris, Oscar Weissman, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Barsky, Edward: Surgery, Oscar Weissman, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Behind the Lines: Daily Life of the Soldiers, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Behind the Lines: Daily Life of the Soldiers, Dentist Getting a Shave, Villa Paz, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Behind the Lines: Daily Life of the Soldiers, 15th Sanidad, Stanley Matajimas and Jack Carpenter, Reading, Ebro Front, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Behind the Lines: Daily Life of the Soldiers, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Behind the Lines: Daily Life of the Soldiers, Dr. Goieng, Bill Gandall, Mike E., circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Behind the Lines: Daily Life of the Soldiers, Oscar Weissman and Unidentified Group, Cordoba, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Behind the Lines: Daily Life of the Soldiers, Stephen Frankel and Philip Rand, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Edward Barsky, Irving Busch, Ramon ?, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, German Gunner, Bruno ?, English/Australian Pilot, Valencia, Jun 1, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, German Gunner, English/Australian Pilot, ?, Bruno ?, Valencia, Jun 1, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Godella, Sep 1, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Behind the Lines: Group, Rest and Relaxation, Peter Paterson, Morris Kornblumn, ?, ?, ?, ?, Frank Ayers, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, ?, Judson Briggs, ?, Dave Davidson, Barcelona, Apr 20, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, ?, ?, ?, ?, ?, Alvah Bessie, Herman (Gabby) Klein, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, (Left to Right) Hermine Hartmann, Ruth Epstein, Hilda and Lisa Garric, Dora Sukalkis, Edyth May Dyer, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, ? Langer, Norman C. Rintz, Theodor Everhard Van Rheemst, A. I. Freedman, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Norman C. Rintz, Theodor Everhard Van Rheemst, ? Langer, ?, Belgian/French Volunteers, Franklin Bissle, Fanny Golub, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Otto Schilling, ?, Hannah "Honey" Herskowitz, Dorothy Fontaine, Norman Rintz, Rose Wachsman, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Ruth Davidow and A. I. Freedman, circa 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Salaria Kee (a.k.a. Salaria Kea), ?, ?, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 100a)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Snowball Fight, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - Belacazar Hospital: Doctor with Patient, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - Belacazar Hospital: School, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - Bell (Roberts), Hilda: At the Beach, Mediterranean [Port Bou?], undated (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Bell (Roberts), Hilda: Pasionara Hospital, Recovery Room, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Bell (Roberts), Hilda: Ruth Epstein, Hermine Hartman, Sidney Vogel, Unidentified Sailor, Murcia, Apr 21, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Bell (Roberts), Hilda: Shipboard with Grace Miriam Margulis and ?, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - Bell (Roberts), Hilda: Shipboard with ?, ?, ?, ?, ?, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - Benjamin, Jos?É¬©: Portrait, Spain[?], circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - Benicasim Hospital: Examination Room with Doctor and Patient, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - Berkowitz, Grace: At the Beach, Mediterranean, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Berkowitz, Grace: Shipboard with Four Volunteers, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Bethune, Norman: Portraits, NYC and Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Bjose, Jack: with Unidentified Woman and Man, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - Blanc, [Delfin G?É¬?mez?]: Doctor with Four Nurses (?), Murcia, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Bombed/Shelled Buildings: General, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - Bombed/Shelled Buildings: Barcelona, Mar 17, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 117)
  - Bombed/Shelled Buildings: Taran?É¬ßon, Dec 3, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Boturnska, Anka: Group, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - Bowers, Eddie: Mural at "English Hospital," Huete, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - Br?É¬©, Fanny: with Spanish Comrade, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Br?É¬©, Fanny: with Two Spanish Comrades, Murcia, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Bresher, Luba: Jack Goldstein, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - Bresson, ?: Javanese Wife of French Photographer Henri Cartier-Bresson with Unidentified Volunteers, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - Briggs, Judson: Groups and Portrait, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Briggs, Judson: Photo of his Painting, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - Briggs, Judson: Portrait, Vera Cruz [Mexico?], undated (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - Bruzzichesi, Anne: Alice Wagnon, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - Busch, Irving: Casualties, Taran?É¬ßon, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - Busch, Irving: En Route to Spain, with Unidentified Man, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Busch, Irving: Edwin Rolfe, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Busch, Irving: Group, Fernanda ?, with Six Others, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Busch, Irving: Group, Three Unidentified Men, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Busch, Irving: Muriel Draper, New York Dinner, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Busch, Irving: Raymond Frank and Unidentified Nurse, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Busch, Irving: Spanish Nurse, Cornelius Peters, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Busch, Irving: Portrait, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Buzzechei, Eve: With Alice Wagnon, circa 1937 - 1938 (Box 11, Folder 138a)
  - Byrne, Albert: Relaxing on Sofa with Thelma Erickson, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Canadian Volunteers: Group, Taran?É¬ßon, circa 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Casualties: General, circa 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Casualties: Granollers, May 31, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chadwick, Selma: Portrait, Spain, circa 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chadwick, Selma: Rest and Relaxation with Jack ?, Prior to Crossing Ebro, Jul 1, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Children's Camp: General, circa 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Children's Camp: Murcia, circa 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Children's Camp: Paul Valliant Couturier, circa 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Children's Camp: Unidentified, circa 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Clipping: Andre Marty with International Brigade Flag, France, circa 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clipping: At the Front, Non-Combat, Teruel, circa 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)